Rathal saw at once that the Unsullied Flame was a gift from the Great Soul.
He resolved to harness its power with technology and created Amaterasu.
By the light of Amaterasu's sacred flame, the people began to rebuild.
With its power, they established a new state in the Far East.
Looks like an old subway station.
That was powerful.
It burned through my coat instantly.
Where's the shooter?
I haven't heard a sound.
But somewhere in the dark.
The young man with the Adola burst, the flame meant to exterminate mankind.
He doesn't belong with you.
I'd like to thank you for bringing him to us.
You've saved us some trouble.
What do you intend to do with Shinra?
Tell me your objective.
Die.
Take what you got and leave now
You're wearing out your welcome
No one here wants to see you
Here, yeah
Think that you won from day one
But the devil will come
You know just why he wants you
Don't you?
Your crooked desire
Left us in history
Miscuited, defighted
In the part of the razor
You started a fighter
You gotta watch it burn
Try to save yourself like you always do
Every bridge we build
You think it's just a burn it down
Just burn it down
When everything is gone
You wish you only heard us out
Heard us out
Screaming
Mkay Shiestion
Mkay!
Went!
Where are you?
I'm completely cut off from the others
And the enemy could appear at any second
I'm stays on his toes man
Hold it.
You okay, Leaked?
Don't move a muscle.
To be honest, Shinra, I...
I've been better.
You're the one with the Adola Burst, right?
If you value this man's life, you'll do as I tell you.
Hurry, Shinra! Use the rabbit!
You know...
The tiger hand sign?
Be quiet!
That's some pretty impressive speed.
The rapid, you said?
That's even cooler than kicker man kick.
With my rapid man kick, I can't be beat!
I think Captain Shinmon's gonna shoot that down, too.
Why do you keep throwing man into everything?
One word. Shinra bansho.
It means all of nature.
And well, since the bond can also be pronounced as man...
There's me!
My little brother!
And then, man!
Right smack between us!
When we bond together, we're Shinra bansho!
That's why I'm says man a lot, man.
Makes perfect sense.
You should explain it to Shinmon like that.
I'm sure it'll go great.
Sounds like Lieutenant Hinoa.
We should go.
The others are fighting the white-clad, too.
The more goons we beat, the less they'll have to.
It seems my position has been compromised.
Snipers using the darkness as cover between attacks, and their fire's too bright to trace back to them.
I used ricochet control to pepper a wide area, but there's no sign I made contact.
Can't get a clean shot with all these obstructions.
I should close in.
At any rate, the enemy knows where I am.
I need to move.
No cover in here.
I need to get through as fast as I can.
The moment he gives us an opening, we'll attack.
He's fighting arrow, remember?
I doubt that we'll get the chance to do anything.
We're both using ranged weapons.
But since I have my ricochet control, I should have the advantage up close.
Did you come in here to try and escape from my arrows?
How ironic.
All you did was trap yourself.
Break.
Damn!
I've stumbled into your hunting ground.
That's right, and I never let my prey escape.
I will be taking the Adola Burst as well.
Your brainwashed zealots, who can't see the value of a human life.
Shinra would never help you.
This scorched world is in a constant state of flux.
It's on the cusp of a great upheaval as we speak.
And in the wake of it, all our feelings will amount to nothing.
Those who insist that their existence has meaning are fools who can't conform themselves to this world.
You say Shinra would never help us, as if he has a choice.
But his feelings don't matter.
The evangelist requires that young man's Adola Burst.
So we will take it.
When you look at yourself as a member of a group,
your feelings as an individual lose importance.
When that group's the size of a country or the world, that gets truer.
At any second, those you care for could burst into flames right in front of you.
So it's probably for the best, if you forego all attachments.
And fulfill your dispassionate role as an insignificant cog in the machine of our society.
One that feels nothing.
There are many people, including me, who think that way.
It's certainly an easier way to live.
Emotions can be downright exhausting.
If that's how you see things, why fight?
First you tell me my soldier's feelings don't matter.
Then you expect me to hand him over?
What do you take me for?
Philosophy aside, you spit fuel in my face?
You'd better expect me to get fired up.
Now that's a spectacle.
It makes a devastating roar.
And a devastating shockwave, too.
I don't get it.
What the hell is he firing?
These are just standard 7.62x51mm bullets.
But with all my power behind them.
They move so fast that I don't need to score a hit.
This sonic boom will do plenty of damage.
He destroys another gun barrel every time he pulls that trigger.
He makes that gun shoot like a cannon.
I wonder if Arrow's all right.
I was looking for an opportunity to finish him.
But that would be like stepping into a shootout between a pair of tanks!
My strength is spent.
Vision's fading fast.
It feels like my eyelids are melting.
I can feel my consciousness drifting away.
Through the dust and darkness of this underground hell,
all that I can make out is the smell of gunpowder.
What's become of...
the other shooter?
When people can burst into flames at random and lose their lives in an instant.
Becoming indifferent about your own life
is a way of devoting yourself to the world.
My death won't change a thing.
Damn you, Obi.
Making me a lieutenant when the 8th is barely even big enough to call a company.
I'd feel guilty leaving you to run things on your own.
If I die down here, then who's gonna teach our rookies discipline?
Know why you couldn't finish me off?
It's because your first shot hit the wrong shoulder.
I won't go down while I wear the emblem of Company 8!
I'll use her flames...
to make it go even faster!
That took a lot out of me.
Doubt I'll be able to move for a while.
It's funny.
I thought that push-past-your-limits stuff
was just a fantasy for gullible kids.
You're the ones behind the fog and the shimmers.
Guess you finally think you can take me, you cowards.
Striking the enemy when they're at their weakest is Tactics 101.
Arrow was best suited to wear you down.
So how does it feel to know that you'll soon die at this coward's hand?
I doubt you have the strength to offer any resistance.
Let me put you to rest.
You would have done me in with that.
A shame it was only a shimmer.
Now die.
That was surprisingly powerful for a last-ditch effort.
Not that it matters when you miss.
No.
I hit my mark.
Though I am descended from the heavens,
I was born from the earth below.
I transverse the land and sky.
I'm a knight.
I saw Arthur watching us through a tiny crack in the ceiling.
Signaled him to come on down.
So you're the pure soul who summoned this heavenly champion down to earth.
What do you need?
Have a quest for me?
Do I really have to explain the situation?
You're good.
His face was covered then.
But I fought the shimmer guy at Vulcans.
Why don't you handle this, Mirage?
Not a problem.
This one's more vulnerable to my shimmers than most.
Kind of a one-trick pony, aren't you?
This one trick has been the end of every foe I've met.
Die!
That attack was fake.
It didn't have the breath of life in it.
Let that stress heighten your awareness.
Feel life around you.
Not just your allies, but your enemies, too.
Focus on the lives at stake,
and you can use the stress of the battle as a tool.
Good. Don't let yourself fall prey to diversions for fate.
You have to discern the attack that's coming to take your life.
Focus.
Harness the tension you're feeling.
Sense the life around you.
Now that I've gained the wisdom of the samurai,
I'm multi-classing as...
a knight samurai.
Hold up.
Let me think this through.
If I were a knight samurai,
I'd be mostly a samurai, right?
That doesn't make sense.
Oh, I had it backwards.
I'm really...
a samurai knight.
Your eyes are great at tracking small movements.
That can help you,
or become a distraction.
Be wary of deceptions and fates.
There's more out there than what the eye can see.
Maybe he's just pretending he can see through my illusions,
trusting I'd probe with my shimmers before attacking.
In that case,
with this large a number attacking en masse,
he'll have to assume the real me is mixed in.
But in truth,
all of them are fake.
A real attack,
the kind that's intended to take your life,
always comes with a distinct breath.
You need to listen for that breath of life.
Like the one I just took!
An attack with the intent to kill
will come with a breath.
The breath of life.
I refuse to get anywhere near you
until you let one of my shimmers distract you
and give me an opening.
The instant I see that opening,
my blade will leap from the shadows
and pierce your throat.
But first...
The breath of life!
The eye caliber attack!
What was that for?
Were you trying to kill me
just because you heard me breathing?
I'm a samurai knight.
My blade knows its enemies.
No.
How did you...
I heard his breath.
While he thought I was distracted,
he tried to sneak up and stab you.
That villain is a knave to his core.
Can you stand?
Impressive work, Arthur.
Where'd the other one go?
I think he ditched his pal and ran off.
What was up with that one's face?
Think he's human?
The man's face was somewhat mask-like.
But what would he be if not a human?
Hmm.
We need to rejoin the others.
Great. Lead the way.
So it goes.
Looks like the tunnel forks off again.
This sucks.
Why is the nether confusing and scary?
Have any ideas about which way we should try?
Do you see what I see?
There's something glowing on the left side.
Two days!
And they're coming toward us!
They're...
My eyes!
Who are you calling an over-dice tunnel troll?
We never said that, we swear!
Oh, hey.
It's you, Maki.
So those demonic eyes were just...
Sputter and flare.
Maki!
It's super scary down here!
There, there.
You'll be safe with me.
Two life signs just showed up out of nowhere.
They're 15 meters away.
We should be able to see them.
Are they on our side?
You will never see a person who is on your side again.
Hey, Lisa.
So you finally gave up and put on the uniform you despised.
You look like a fool in it, Vulcan.
You know that, right?
And you look great in whatever you wear.
You've always hated the Fire Force more than anything.
So what would make you follow them underground?
How is that a question?
I obviously came down here to see you, Lisa.
What's the matter, feeler?
Are you forgetting who it was that gave you a home?
Who accepted a filthy, ignorant cat like you?
And taught you everything you know?
Who showed you how to manipulate fire?
How to manipulate men?
You only gained Vulcan's affection by using the techniques I taught you.
He only took you in because you followed my teachings.
Without me, you are nothing.
Nothing but a stupid, dirty cat.
Understand, or do you need another lesson?
Get the hell away from her!
You should know my true name is Fila.
And that I am a knight of the Ashen Flames.
That's right.
Protect me with your life.
Yes, sir.
He's lying to you, damn it!
Shut up!
The Iron Matillo?
Something tells me that your lessons did Lisa more harm than good.
But regardless, teaching the youth is just what grown-ups do.
So stop pretending she owes you, you geezer!
Come to think of it, you're quite ignorant too.
Feckless captain of the eighth.
You can call me what you want.
You don't even know what the flames of human combustion are.
But our evangelist knows everything.
Why the spontaneous human combustion phenomenon is assaulting our world.
The true nature of the bugs that have created artificial infernals.
The secret behind Shinra Kusukabe's Adola Burst.
Why his fire is known to us as the flame of perdition.
What happened to this world in the past?
And what is happening to it as we speak?
The evangelist knows all this and more.
But I will not share that knowledge.
It sounds like you really are a lousy teacher.
You're an intriguing man.
I will not share that knowledge.
You